Finding Aid for the David C. Copley collection of costume designs LSC.2210
UCLA Library Special Collections
David C. Copley collection of costume designs
1922-2006, undated
UCLA Library Special Collections
Copley, David C.
David C. Copley Foundation
LSC.2210
36 linear feet (17 oversize flat boxes, 2 boxes)
David C. Copley's collection consists of approximately 502 costume sketches representing designs for film, television, and theatre productions (possibly community theatre). Represented are the designs of many talented costume designers such as: Adrian, Cecil Beaton, Donfeld, Morton Haack, Edith Head, Dorothy Jeakins, Elois Jenssen, Charles LeMaire, Jean Louis, Bob Mackie, Walter Plunkett, Helen Rose, Anthea Sylbert, Travilla, and Theadora Van Runkle. Materials date from 1922 to 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
Unprocessed collection. Material is unavailable for access. Please see LSC's Access to Unprocessed Collections Policy for more information about levels of discovery and access of special collections materials and registering interest in unprocessed collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the David C. Copley Foundation, 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9992501783606533
Biographical History
Philanthropist David C. Copley (1952-2012) was an American publishing heir, on the board of the Copley Press for over thirty years, becoming president and owner, as well as publisher of the San Diego Union-Tribune.
Scope and Contents
David C. Copley's collection consists of approximately 502 costume sketches representing designs for film, television, and theatre productions (possibly community theatre). Represented are the designs of many talented costume designers such as: Adrian, Cecil Beaton, Donfeld, Morton Haack, Edith Head, Dorothy Jeakins, Elois Jenssen, Charles LeMaire, Jean Louis, Bob Mackie, Walter Plunkett, Helen Rose, Anthea Sylbert, Travilla, and Theadora Van Runkle.
Costume design drawings; Costume design.; David C. Copley Foundation
- Aghayan, Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Anderson, Milo, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Anderson, Milo?, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Balkan, Adele, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Banton, Travis, 1927-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Beaton, Cecil, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Brown, Lewis, 1970-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bear, Jack, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Berliner, Charles Italian Straw Hat, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Best, Marjorie, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Canfield or Campbell, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dodson, Mary Kay, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dryden, Ernst, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Du Bois, Raoul Pene, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Edelstein, Victor, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Estevez, Luis, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Forse, Roger, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Gunn, Archie, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Greer, Howard, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Hubert, Rene, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Brooks, D., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Colasanti - Moore, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Domergue, Jean Gabriel, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Danfeld, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Gauter, Jean Paul, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Grant, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Head, Edith (1 of 2), 1946-1952 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Head, Edith (2 of 2), 1935-1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Jeakins, Dorothy, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Lee, Rene, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Haack, Morton, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Klotz, Florence, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Lentz, Irene, 1945-1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Maas, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Mabry, Moss, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Mackie, Bob, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Mendleson, Anthony, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Miller, Jack, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Miller, Nolan, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Moss, Sylvia, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Murin, David, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Myers, Ruth, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Nelle, Anthony, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Novarese, Nino, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Palmer, Adele, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Goldstein, Jess, 2003-2005 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Fletcher, Robert, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Balmain, Pierre, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Versace, Giani, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Shoup, Howard, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Theiss, William, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Fonteray, Jacques, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Unidentified [Zig], undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Adrian, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bakst, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Erte, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Kelley, Orry, 1930-1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Larthe, Paul R., 1937 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Meneke, Pete, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Plunkett, Walter (4 of 4), 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Toms, Carl, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Weber, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Rose, 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- McCoy, Herschel, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- LeMaire, Charles, 1922-1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Leet, Margaret, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Louis, Jean, 1962-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Neil, Warden, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Nickels, Al, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- O'Brien, Sheila, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Pakledinaz, Martin, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Perdziola, Robert, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Rose, Helen, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Roth, Ann, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Autrea Original, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Jupiter's Darling, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Unidentified - Kathryn Grayson, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Unidentified [Tamino - character], undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Sanders, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Routh, May, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Sylbert, Anthea, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Steele, Giles, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Santiago, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Turner, Ret, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Travilla, Bill (1 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Travilla, Bill (2 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Valles (1 of 2), 1949 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Valles (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Van Runkle, Theadora, 1966-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Wills, Mary, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Wood, Yvonne, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Unidentified artist, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Unidentified artist, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Unidentified artist, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Plunkett, Walter (1 of 4), 1939-1956 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Plunkett, Walter (2 of 4), 1932-1947 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Plunket, Walter (3 of 4), 1939 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Plunkett GWTW, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Jensen, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Poiret, Paul, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Powell, Anthony ("Hook"), 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Stracciari, Luigi, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Johnson, Gertrude, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Travis, Michael, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Salling, Norman, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Sascha, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Sicango, Eduardo, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Stewart, Marlene, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Taylor, Noel, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Visart, Natalie, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Zuber, Catherine, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Andrew Shelton as "The Frog Prince", undated (Box 17)
  Scope and Contents
  One framed drawing
- David Copley as "The Beast" by "ON", undated (Box 17)
- Lee, Rene (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials are restricted due to conservation issues.
- Head, Edith (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Jenssen, Eloise (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Research clippings, drawing tags, undated (Box 19)